A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 17727-19980 FA739G
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Statement to the Society of Fellows, University of Michigan, May 1 (Reports 018707), 1970; Bundy, McGeorge
  Statement in support of the creation of a Society of Fellows at the University of Michigan.
  Education, Higher -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.
- Remarks at the International Ex-students Conference, University of Texas, May 15 (Reports 018708), 1970; Bundy, McGeorge
  Statement on the war in Vietnam and American foreign affairs at the University of Texas.
  Vietnam War, 1961-1975; International cooperation
- Statement on unification of NET/Channel 13, June 29 (Reports 018709), 1970; Bundy, McGeorge
  Public broadcasting -- United States; Television in education -- United States
- What is learning and who does it?, August 3 (Reports 018710), 1970; Bundy, McGeorge
  Statement on the learning process and education in America.
  Learning and scholarship -- United States; Education -- United States
- Remarks at a symposium on "Looking at the seventies," American Bar Association, St Louis, August 12 (Reports 018711), 1970; Bundy, McGeorge
  Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Nuclear arms control -- International cooperation
- Statement on the support of public interest law, Center for Law and Social Policy (Reports 018712), 1970; Bundy, McGeorge
  Public interest law -- United States
- Damn the absolute: notes on authority and autonomy, the Scottish Council (Development and Industry), November 11 (Reports 018713), 1970; Bundy, McGeorge
  Autonomy -- Scotland; Nuclear arms control -- International relations
- Remarks at AP Managing Editors Association Convention, Honolulu, Hawaii, November 20 (Reports 018714), 1970; Bundy, McGeorge
  Journalism -- Societies, etc.; News agencies -- United States
- The consideration of the Geneva Protocol of 1925 -- statement before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, March 12 (Reports 018715), 1971; Bundy, McGeorge
  Biological arms control -- International cooperation; Biological warfare (International law)
- Hearings on S. 731, bill to regulate undeclared war -- statement before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, April 26 (Reports 018716), 1971; Bundy, McGeorge
  War and emergency powers -- United States
- Remarks at the American Society of International Law, Washington, D. C., April 29 (Reports 018717), 1971; Bundy, McGeorge
  Remarks on a bill about the declaration of war.
- Remarks at the Endowment Conference, The University Club, May 5 (Reports 018718), 1971; Bundy, McGeorge
  Remarks on the management of charitable endowments.
- Remarks at the Stevenson Lecture, Chatham House, London, November 30 (Reports 018719), 1971; Bundy, McGeorge
  Remarks on the establishment of better international relations following the 1960's.
  Nuclear arms control -- International cooperation; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; International trade
- Remarks on the announcement of the estabilshment of the Cable Television Information Center, Washington, D. C., January 11 (Reports 018720), 1972; Bundy, McGeorge
  Title suffient as abstract.
  Broadcast television -- United States; Public television -- United States
- Ford Foundation activities and Washington State, March 10 (Reports 018721), 1972; Bundy, McGeorge
  Endowments -- Ford Foundation; Washington (State) -- United States
- Remarks at the National Jewish Welfare Board's biennial convention, Atlanta, April 13 (Reports 018722), 1972; Bundy, McGeorge
  Social justice -- United States
- Responsibilities of the philanthropic stockholder -- report on a special case: ten propositions on trial at the Ford Foundation summary of remarks at Investment Company Institute, Washington, D. C., May 19 (Reports 018723), 1972; Bundy, McGeorge
- Summary of remarks to Subcommittee on national security policy, House Foreign Affairs Committee, May 24 (Reports 018724), 1972; Bundy, McGeorge
  Nuclear arms control -- International cooperation; Russia (Federation) -- International cooperation; Vietnam War, 1961-1975
- Justice as fairness between men and women -- American Council on Education 55th annual meeting, Miami Beach, October 6 (Reports 018725), 1972; Bundy, McGeorge
  Statement regarding women in higher education.
  Women -- Education, Higher -- United States
- Statement on grant to Dalhousi University, November 17 (Reports 018726-001), 1972; Bundy, McGeorge
  Research grants -- Education, Higher -- Canada
- An American looks at the European Community, November 29 (Reports 018726-002), 1972; Bundy, McGeorge
  Europe -- International cooperation -- Commerce
- Statement on the National Urban Coalition, January 10 (Reports 018727), 1973; Bundy, McGeorge
  Urban renewal -- Citizen participation; Urban policy -- United States
- Speech at Foundation luncheon group meeting, March 22 (Reports 018728), 1973; Bundy, McGeorge
- Statement to the Subcommittee on Domestic Finance, committee on banking and currency, U.S. House of Representatives, April 5 (Reports 018729), 1973; Bundy, McGeorge
  Remarks on a bill relating to investment income of private foundations.
  Endowments -- Ford Foundation; Finance, Public -- Accounting -- Ford Foundation
- Statement to the Subcommittee on Communication and Power, committee on interstate and foreign commerce, U.S. House of Representatives, June 12 (Reports 018730), 1973; Bundy, McGeorge
  Statement in support of HR 8538, a bill related to public broadcasting.
  Public broadcasting -- United States; Public television -- Law and legislation
- Preliminary statement to the Commission for the Organization of Government, June 25 (Reports 018731), 1973; Bundy, McGeorge
  Statement on the state of foreign affairs.
- Toward an open foreign policy -- the opportunity and the problem, October 15 (Reports 018732), 1973; Bundy, McGeorge
  Statement on the state of affairs around the world.
- Statement to the National Council on Philanthropy (Reports 018733), 1973; Bundy, McGeorge
  Endowments -- United States
- Private institutions in the public service: an old tradition in a new day, November 2 (Reports 018734), 1973; Bundy, McGeorge
  Charities -- United States; Endowments -- United States
- Talk on the changing international order, India International Centre, February 19 (Reports 018735), 1974; Bundy, McGeorge
  International relations -- India -- United States
- Forbes Magazine transcript, March 25 (Reports 018736), 1974; Bundy, McGeorge
  Q&A on the Ford Foundation.
- Statement to the Senate Subcommittee on intergovernmental Relations, May 22 (Reports 018737), 1974; Bundy, McGeorge
  Appearance before the Senate to partake in hearings on secrecy in government.
  Executive privilege (Government information) -- United States
- Goron School Price Day, June 12 (Reports 018738), 1974; Bundy, McGeorge
  Address to Groton School.
  Trusts and trustees
- Future of world events and development, June 15 (Reports 018739), 1974; Bundy, McGeorge
  Looking 50 years into the future of world events and developments.
- The moral and social responsibilities of the trustees of foundations, Ciba Foundation's 25th anniversary symposium, June 17 (Reports 018740), 1974; Bundy, McGeorge
  Trusts and trustees -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations
- Remarks to the staff of the Ford Foundation, September 27 (Reports 018741), 1974; Bundy, McGeorge
- You are all the same side (Reports 018742), 1974; Bundy, McGeorge
  An informal message to public broadcasting from the president of the Ford Foundation as he accepts, on that institution's behalf, the Distinguished Service Award of the NAEB
  Endowments -- Ford Foundation; Public broadcasting -- United States
- Remarks to the staff of the Ford Foundation, December 16 (Reports 018743), 1974; Bundy, McGeorge
- Prepared comment for Tokyo Philanthropy Symposium, January 17 (Reports 018744), 1975; Bundy, McGeorge
  Endowments -- Ford Foundation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations
- On understanding and reconciliation notes for the commencement after Vietnam, remarks at the University of Texas, Austin, May 17 (Reports 018745), 1975; Bundy, McGeorge
  Statement regarding the approach to foreign policy in the future.
  Vietnam War, 1961-1975; International relations
- Statement to the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, Subcommitte on Foreign Assistance, June 3 (Reports 018746), 1975; Bundy, McGeorge
  Statement regarding the direction of foreign assistance.
  Economic assistance
- Statement to the press, June 11 (Reports 018747), 1975; Bundy, McGeorge
  Statement regarding approval to CIA to assassinate.
  Executive orders -- United States; Intelligence service -- United States; Espionage -- United States; United States. Central Intelligence Agency
- Statement to the House Select Committee on Intelligence, December 10 (Reports 018748), 1975; Bundy, McGeorge
  Discussion on the advantages and disadvantages of covert operations conducted by the Central Intelligence Agency.
  Espionage -- United States; Intelligence service -- United States; United States. Central Intelligence Agency
- Remarks at the Southeast Foundations Conference, October 21 (Reports 018750), 1976; Bundy, McGeorge
- Remarks on the resignation of Henry Ford II from the Ford Foundation -- first draft, January 28 (Reports 018751), 1977; Bundy, McGeorge
  On December 11, 1976, Henry Ford II resigned from the Ford Foundation. His resignation marked the culmination of a process he himself had deliberately set in motion more that twenty-fine year ealier: a process by which, after the great bequests of his fat
- Remarks to the Connecticut Housing Investment Fund Dinner in Hartford, March 2 (Reports 018752), 1977; Bundy, McGeorge
  Housing -- Ford Foundation -- United States; Civil rights -- United States
- Statement before the Carnegie Commission on the future of public broadcasting, February 21 (Reports 018753), 1978; Bundy, McGeorge
- Statement regarding the Bakke Decision, June 28 (Reports 018754), 1978; Bundy, McGeorge
  Affirmative action programs -- United States; Judgments -- United States
- Attracting and maintaining a supply of effective accounting teachers (Reports 018755), 1956; Thomas A. Carroll
  Teachers -- Training of -- Accounting; Teachers -- Supply and demand -- Accounting
- Business education for competence and responsibility (Reports 018756), 1956; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Business -- Study and teaching
- Education for business: a dynamic concept and process address delivered at Accounting Hall of Fame Award Banquet, Ohio State University, Columbus, May 16 (Reports 018757), 1957; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
- The role of the Ford Foundation in business education, Williamstown, MA, August 28 (Reports 018758), 1958; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Business -- Study and teaching; Endowments -- Ford Foundation
- Where is business education going?, Conference of New England deans of collegiate schools of business, Cambridge, MA, October 30 (Reports 018759), 1958; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
- Ford Foundation activities in economics and business administration, sixth annual conference on the economic outlook, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, November 3 (Reports 018760), 1958; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Industrial management; Economics; Endowments -- Ford Foundation
- New horizons in education for business -- address at dedication of new building for School of Business and Public Administration, the University of Missouri, Columbia, MO, March 25 (Reports 018761), 1960; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
- A foundation looks at community action on the problems of older people, August 4 (Reports 018762), 1960; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Older people
- The world-wide management development outlook, Stanford Business Conference, Stanford, CA, September 12 (Reports 018763), 1960; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Executives -- Training of
- A national foundation expresses its interest in the problems of older people, January 9 (Reports 018764), 1961; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
- The world-wide scope of education for business, Bringham Young University, Provo, UT, January 23 (Reports 018765), 1961; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
- Trends in education for business, 28th annual business conference, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, May 10 (Reports 018766), 1958; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
- The next quarter century in business education, West Virginia University, Morgantown, WV, November 22 (Reports 018767), 1957; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
- Where is business education going?, annual meeting, Association of Canadian Schools of Commerce and Business Administration, Edmonton, Alberta, June 8 (Reports 018768), 1958; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
- Round table on the organization and financing of economic research: a case study, December 27 (Reports 018769), 1958; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Economics -- Research; Endowments -- Ford Foundation
- Continuing education and individual responsibility, talk for Air Force Management Group, Tinker Air Force Base, Oklahoma, March 26 (Reports 018770), 1959; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Continuing education -- United States; Educational accountability
- The role of research in the college of business administration, Southwestern Social Science Association, Galveston, TX, March 27 (Reports 018771), 1959; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Industrial management -- Research
- The co-operative role of business in research, May 23 (Reports 018772), 1959; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Business -- Research; Education, Cooperative
- The scholar in our times, Providence, RI, November 20 (Reports 018773), 1959; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Statement on the need to raise expenditure in higher education.
  Universities and colleges -- Research; Education, Higher -- Appropriations and expenditures
- Higher education for business: a forward look, centennial program on education for management in business and industry, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, LA, January 14 (Reports 018774), 1960; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Business -- Education (Higher)
- Trends in professional education for management -- conference on research developments in personnel management, University of California Los Angeles, February 3 (Reports 018775), 1960; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Industrial management -- Education (Higher); Industrial management -- Research
- A foundation expresses its interest in higher education for business management, Ithaca, NY, September 1 (Reports 018776), 1960; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Industrial management -- Education (Higher); Endowments -- Research -- Ford Foundation
- The three careers of Frank Whittemore Abrams, Pierre Hotel, NYC, October 19 (Reports 018777), 1960; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
  Careers -- Abrams, Frank Whittemore
- A world-wide look at education for business, Carbondale, IL, October 20 (Reports 018778), 1960; Carroll, Thomas Henry, 1914-1964
- Taped notes from meeting on program support in the Philippines, Pakistan and Brazil, June 30 (Reports 018779), 1966; Case, Harry L. (Harry Lawrence), 1907-
  Address on program support in the Philippines, Pakistan and Brazil.
  Economic assistance -- Philippines; Economic assistance -- Pakistan; Economic assistance -- Brazil; Economic development projects
- Coming of middle age in higher education, November 13 (Reports 018780), 1972; Cheit, Earl F. (Earl Frank), 1926-2014
  Addressing growth and evolution problems of higher education institutions.
- The new depression in higher education -- implications for the foundations, May 30 (Reports 018781), 1973; Cheit, Earl F. (Earl Frank), 1926-2014
  Addressing the financial problems of higher education institutions and the implications for foundations.
  Endowments -- Education, Higher -- United States
- The indispensable element of greatness, May 7 (Reports 018782), 1960; Cole, Fred C.
  Commencement address at Washington and Lee University.
  Baccalaureate addresses -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States; Education, Humanistic -- United States
- Comments on the functions of a university (Reports 018783), 1961; Cole, Fred C.
  Statement regarding the functions of a university.
- Social dynamite in our large cities, May 24 (Reports 018784), 1961; Conant, James Bryant
- Problems relative to the introduction of mass communications media for educational purposes in Asia, June 14 (Reports 018785), 1961; Conant, Theodore R.
  Communication -- Education -- Asia; Mass media -- Education -- Asia
- Politics and policies in college admissions, December 4 (Reports 018786), 1964; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Education, Higher -- Admission -- United States
- Opportunity redefined, April 6 (Reports 018787), 1965; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Commencement address delivered to the Agricultural and Technical College of North Carolina, in Greensboro, N.C.
  Baccalaureate addresses -- United States
- The prospects of education, April 8 (Reports 018788), 1965; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Remarks delivered at a meeting of New York State college admission personnel in Buffalo, NY.
  Education -- Aims and objectives -- United States
- Karl T. Compton: a tribute, October 22 (Reports 018789), 1955; Gaither, H. Rowan (Horace Rowan), 1909-1961
  Memorial service
- Reflections from outside, February 28 (Reports 018790), 1966; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  These reflections are organized around three related themes or trends which are of concern to you in the two-year college movement and to us in the foundations.
  Junior colleges -- Education, Higher -- United States; Educational equalization -- Education, Higher -- United States
- Commencement speech -- Perkiomen School, June 5 (Reports 018791), 1966; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Commencement addresses; Intergenerational relations
- Commencement address -- Wiley College, Marshall, TX, May 22 (Reports 018792), 1967; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Baccalaureate addresses -- Education, Higher -- African Americans -- United States; Social change
- Heavy burdens at the narrow gates: the American Negro and higher education, October 6 (Reports 018793), 1967; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Remarks delivered at the 23rd National Conference of the Association of College Admissions Counselors.
  Education, Higher -- African Americans -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Admission
- Taking aim at a moving target, August 8 (Reports 018794), 1972; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Remarks delivered at the Seventh Annual Conference of the Society for College and University Planning, Atlanta, GA.
  Education, Higher -- United States; Educational planning
- Changing patterns of undergraduate education, November 8 (Reports 018795), 1974; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Remarks delivered at the Danforth Foundation's Institute for College Development Workshop, Salishan Lodge, Gleneden Beach, OR.
  Education, Higher -- United States; Educational change
- Career prospects in higher education, April 29 (Reports 018796), 1975; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Graduate students who hope to embark upon careers in higher education face a seriously depressed labor market.
  Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Faculty; College teachers
- Equality, equity or equilibrium: some policy considerations respecting access to higher education (Reports 018797), 1976; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Anyone responsible for shaping higher education access policies is likely to become an equilibrist.
  Education, Higher -- United States; Educational equalization
- It's incredible, to say the most!, April 26 (Reports 018798), 1977; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Higher education was -- and to some extent still is -- advertised as the most effective and fastest acting all-purpose panacea guaranteed to give both instant and long-term relief.
- Faculty collective bargaining: impact on planning, July 22 (Reports 018799), 1976; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Institutional planning is an integral element of institutional governance and must be seen in context.[p. 1]
  Education, Higher -- United States; Collective bargaining -- College teachers; Educational planning
- Ten, Remarks delivered at the District I Conference of the Council for the Advancement and Support of Education, January 29 (Reports 018800), 1980; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  Remarks prepared for delivery at the District I Conference of the Council for the Advancement and Support of Education.
  Education, Higher -- United States; Endowments; Educational planning
- Learning to cope with a downward slope, May 8 (Reports 018801), 1980; Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene), 1920-
  "A few days ago the American Council on Education, on behalf of several Washington-based associations, released a study entitled, 'College Enrollment: Testing the Conventional Wisdom Against the Facts.' It declares that doomsayers who predict significant
  Education, Higher -- United States; Educational planning; Independent study; School enrollment
- Talk on his European trip (Reports 018802), 1954; David, Donald K.
  Dean David's remarks fall into two categories: (1) his interest in the development of business education in Europe and (2) his overall interest, as a Trustee of the Ford Foundation, in significant features of the European economic scene outside the field
  Business education -- Education, Higher -- Europe
- Giving is good business, May 10 (Reports 018803), 1956; David, Donald K.
  It is indeed an honor to receive you William Penn award, and I am deeply grateful.
  Endowments
- Remarks at Reed College, Portland, OR, September 13 (Reports 018804), 1957; David, Donald K.
  From its beginning, Reed College has been at the mission of revealing the freshness of ideas, the vitality of life.
  Education, Humanistic -- Education, Higher -- United States
- The new relationship of business to society, September 5 (Reports 018805), 1958; David, Donald K.
  The last fifty years have seen great changes in business and the climate in which it operates. Those who planned the Harvard Business School half a century ago could hardly have foreseen these changes.
  Business education -- Education, Higher -- United States
- Business education for America and the free world (Reports 018806), 1960; David, Donald K.
  "Nearly every professor--and most of all, a retired dean--hopes he has earned the esteem of his professional colleagues. But rarely are we so daring as to hope to win the regard of students as well as faculty." [p. 7]
  Business education -- Education, Higher
- Philanthropy is everybody's business, talk before the Greenville County Foundation, Greenville, S.C., November 21 (Reports 018807), 1961; David, Donald K.
  "The growth of this region, the development and diversification of both its economic and its social structure, are among the truly outstanding achievements of the postwar period. It has taken great effort. It has created considerable strain. But progress
- Address just before a luncheon given at The University of the West Indies, Kingston, Jamaica, October 23 (Reports 018808), 1964; David, Donald K.
  ...You cannot build your own institutuions now and relate them to the rest of the world later-- as we did. Your task is infinitely more difficult... [p. 2]
  Education, Higher -- Jamaica
- Remarks at Pasadena Civic Auditorium, April 24 (Reports 018809), 1951; Davis, Chester C. (Chester Charles), 1887-
  The Trustees declared last fall that the Ford Foundation will support activities directed toward the development among the peoples of the world of the understanding and conditions essential to the permanent peace... [p. 1]
  Exchange of persons programs -- International cooperation